<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <p>
  
  </p>
  <a name="Purpose"> </a>
  <h3>Purpose</h3>
  <p>
    The "why" goes here
  </p>
  <a name="Project"> </a>
  <h3>Current Project</h3>
   <p>
    Description of project goes here
  </p>
    <a name="Workflows"> </a>
  <h3>RTLS Storyboards</h3>
  <p>
  The following storyboards illustrate the data workflows addressed by this implementation guide. Note that in these scenarios, tracker tag 
  assignments are assumed to occur in a system other than the real time location system (e.g. the EHR). If tag assignment workflows occur in the RTLS, 
  the sending system and receiving system would be switched for the first three storyboards.
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow1"> </a>
  <h4>Tracking Tag Assigned to Patient</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates notifying a RTLS that a specific tracking tag has been assigned to a specific patient.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Adam Everyman arrives at the Good Health Hospital Emergency Room via car with a broken left hand. Christopher Clerk, the emergency room clerk 
  registers and checks in Mr. Everyman then assigns him a unique RTLS tracking device with a tag ID of E1124. The EHR system sends a FHIR Messaging 
  Bundle to the RTLS to associate Mr. Everyman with tag E1124, containing a Device resource that references a Patient resource in Device.subject.
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow2"> </a>
  <h4>Tracking Tag Assigned to Provider</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates notifying a RTLS that a specific tracking tag has been assigned to a specific healthcare practitioner.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Dr. Ellen Emergency is a new physician in the Emergency Department of Good Health Hospital. She is issued a new photo id with embedded tracking tag 
  S4567, and the personnel system sends a FHIR Messaging Bundle to the RTLS to associate Dr. Ellen with tag S4567, containing a Device resource that 
  references a Practitioner resource in Device.subject.
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow3"> </a>
  <h4>Tracking Tag Assigned to Device</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates notifying a RTLS that a specific tracking tag has been assigned to a specific device.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  On Tuesday morning, the Good Health Hospital receiving department delivered a new portable x-ray machine to the Emergency Department. Ms. Technician 
  fastens tracking tag X-21 to the machine and records that assignment in the Emergency Department administrative system, which sends a FHIR Messaging 
  Bundle to the RTLS containing a Device resource that references another Device resource in Device.parent, associating the x-ray machine with tag X-21.
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow4"> </a>
  <h4>Tracking Tag Unassignment</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates notifying a RTLS that a specific tracking tag is no longer assigned to a specific patient, provider, or device.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Adam Everyman was treated for his broken hand and Dr. Ellen Emergency thinks he is ready to go home and recover. Mr. Everyman proceeds to the registration 
  desk where Christopher Clerk completes Mr. Everyman's discharge and takes the RTLS tracking device that was assigned to him. The EHR system sends a FHIR 
  Messaging Bundle to the RTLS without any references to a patient or any other resources, disassociating the tracking tag from Mr. Everyman.
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow5"> </a>
  <h4>Tracking Tag Location Update</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates a RTLS notifying other systems that a particular subject (patient, provider, or device) has moved to a new location.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Mr. Everyman is checked into the Emergency Department and issued an RTLS tracking tag. He is then escorted to room 12A where he waits for the physician on duty, 
  Dr. Ellen Emergency. The RTLS notes Mr. Everyman's new location and sends a Subscription Notification Bundle to the EHR containing a Device resource that references 
  a Location resource with the updated patient location.
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow6"> </a>
  <h4>Co-Location Update</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates a RTLS notifying other systems that a particular patient and healthcare practitioner or other tracked resource are in the same location.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Dr. Ellen Emergency walks into Mr. Everyman's room and checks Mr. Everyman's hand. The RTLS notes Dr. Emergency's new location and initiates a Provider Location 
  Updated notification to the EHR. The RTLS also computes that the tracking tags for Mr. Everyman and Dr. Emergency are located within the same service 
  delivery location, and sends a Subscription Notification Bundle to the EHR containing...
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow7"> </a>
  <h4>Tag Auxiliary Function Performed</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates a RTLS notifying other systems that an auxiliary function (e.g. button press) was performed for a particular tracking tag associated with a patient, 
  provider, or device and sends a subrscription notification Bundle to the EHR containing a Device resource that identifies the tracking tag and an Observation resource that indicates 
  the auxiliary function that was performed.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Insert narrative here
  </p>
  <a name="Workflow8"> </a>
  <h4>Tag Status Update</h4>
  <p>
  This storyboard demonstrates a RTLS notifying other systems that there is a status change (e.g. battery health, active/inactive) for a particular tracking tag that may or may not be associated with a patient, 
  provider, or device and sends a notification containing a Device resource that specifies the change in tracking tag status.
  </p>
  <p>
  <b>Narrative</b>
  </p>
  <p>
  Insert narrative here
  </p>
</div>
