<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <!-- The spaces between the open and close "a" tag are mandatory.  (Cuz HTML renderers are dumb...) -->
  <a name="intro"> </a>
  <h3>Overview</h3>
	<p>
    This implementation guide defines the use of FHIR R4 resources to exchange information that indicates where patients, staff, devices, 
  or other assets are located within a hospital or other healthcare facility.
  </p>
  <p>
    A Real Time Location System (RTLS) captures, process, and stores information about the location of tracking tags. These tags are associated to an assigned subject 
  (patients, providers, devices) and their location data is typically exchanged between a RTLS system and other healthcare systems as they move around a healthcare facility. This data 
  can be used for many applications such as workflow automation, staff/asset tracking, and patient monitoring.
  </p>
  <a name="scope"> </a>
	<h3>Scope</h3>
	<p>
    The scope of this implementation guide includes support for workflows related to communication between a RTLS and another healthcare system, such as Electronic Health 
  Record (EHR) software. This includes the following:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <li>
      Tag location updates
    </li>
    <li>
      Tag assignment and unassignment for patients, staff, or devices
    </li>
    <li>
      Tag colocation notifications
    </li>
    <li>
      Tag auxiliary functions (e.g. button presses)
    </li>
    <li>
      Tag health updates (e.g. battery state)
    </li>
    <li>
      Addition and removal of tags from circulation
    </li>
  </ul>
  <p>
    This specification addresses tracking only of patients, providers, and devices. Other subjects/resources in the healthcare setting such as supplies and pharmaceuticals 
  may be tracked by some systems. 
  </p>
  <a name="walkthrough"> </a>
  <h3>IG Structure</h3>
  <p>
    This implementation guide is organized into the following main sections:
  </p>
  <ul>
    <table>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="background.html">Background</a></td>
        <td>Introduces key workflows and concepts that are relevant for implementating this specification.</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="spec.html">Specification</a></td>
        <td>Insert description here</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="artifacts.html">Artifact Index</a></td>
        <td>Provides a list of the FHIR artifacts defined as part of this implementation guide.</td>
      </tr>
    </table>
  </ul>
</div>